♬ Changing ♬
Airborne Toxic Event
* All these buckets of rain *
* I've heard enough about it *
* you say that I lied *
* I am a gentleman *
* didn't I ask for a place I could stay *
* what were we both thinking *
* the next part just got in the way *
* you were just always talking about changing *
* changing *
* what if I was the same then *
* same then *
* the same I always was *
* all these things that you say *
이봐! 조심해!
Hey,watch it!
* The mind-numbing games that you play *
* I am a gentleman *
* didn't I pay for every laugh,every dime *
Excuse me,I wasn't getting out of line.
Just needed to--
죄송한데, 줄에서
나간 게 아니라...
you're the one who almost ran me over.
잠깐, 당신이 날
차로 칠 뻔했죠?
I didn't see anyone at the O.H.B. crosswalk.
횡단보도엔 아무도
없었는데요
횡단보도에 있던 건
아니었어요
Well,I wasn't actually in the crosswalk. There you go.
그럼 됐네요
Drip coffee. Black.
드립 커피요
블랙으로요
THANK YOU.
고마워요
Two,lots of milk and lots of sugar.
두 잔이요
우유랑 설탕 많이요
커피예요
Coffee.
At your 10:00.
당신의...
10시 방향이에요
Thanks.
고마워요
This Alpha Barbie almost mowed me down
이 "알파 바비"가 아침에
날 주차장에 뭉갤 뻔하더니
in the parking lot this morning,and then she took my spot in line
커피 사려는데도
내 앞자리에 껴들었어요
at the coffee cart. You had me at "Alpha Barbie."
알파 바비란 말에
귀가 쫑긋하네요
So the day's already conspiring against you?
벌써부터
일진이 사나워요?
Yes.
맞아요
옷차림은 결혼식이에요?
장례식이에요?
Are you dressed for a wedding or a funeral?
A little bit of both.
양쪽 다 조금씩
섞였죠
You are standing in front of the new head
of the Office of Congressional Affairs.
당신은 지금 의회사무국의
새로운 책임자 앞에 서있어요
굉장하네요!
축하해요
That's huge!
Congratulations!
Thanks.
고마워요
잠깐만요
Wait.
Your desk isn't cleaned up. It's cleaned off.
책상을 청소한 게 아니라
아예 치웠군요
You're leaving?
날 떠나는 거예요?
Well,you went from thrilled for me to sad for you in two seconds.
단 2초 만에 감격에서
슬픔으로 넘어가네요
You're gonna lose your covert status.
비밀 신분을
상실하겠군요
당신과 만날 수는 있나요?
Am I gonna be able to see you? We'll make it work.
만날 수 있을 거예요
But not like this. Not every day.
지금처럼은 아니겠죠
매일 볼 수도 없을 거고요
Believe it or not,this was a very hard decision.
믿기 힘들지도 모르지만
정말 어려운 결정이었어요
And I'll still be keeping an eye on you,so to speak.
여전히 당신을
지켜봐줄 거예요
말이 그렇다고요
The O.C.A. is a great job.
It is.
OCA는 대단한 자리예요
맞아요
And you'll be on the seventh floor with the big boys.
7층에서 거물들과
함께하게 되겠군요
Can always come by and visit.
언제든 들러도 좋아요
Just make an appointment first.
약속만 먼저
잡아두면요
Groan. Eye roll.
복잡한 심정이에요
Briefing time,Annie.
브리핑 시간이에요
애니
누구는 일진이
괜찮아지겠네요
Sounds like somebody's day is about to get better.
I heard something about NASA. Really?
나사와 관련한
얘기를 들었는데
정말요?
You've forgotten me already.
벌써 날 잊었군요
Good luck today.
잘해요, 오늘
Thanks.
고마워요
Have fun with the astronauts.
우주 비행사들과
즐거운 시간 보내요
This area of Northwestern Colombia
여기 콜롬비아의
북서지방은
is now friendly to Colombia's rebel army,FARC.
현재 콜롬비아 반군, 파크에
우호적인 지역이야
Just to orient you,
설명해주자면
Colombia's Batallon Cartagena military base.
여긴 바탈론 카르타헤나
콜롬비아 군기지야
This is what our analysts saw
어제 이 지역을
우리 분석가들이
over Batallon Cartagena for two hours yesterday.
두 시간 동안
관찰한 영상이야
지역이 어둡게 변했어
The area went dark.
The first images following the blackout
정전 복구 이후
처음 들어온 영상엔
기지 주변에 적어도
열 대의 LAV장갑차가 있었지
show at least ten LAV-150s near the base's perimeter.
파크가 행동에
들어간 거예요
FARC's spreading its wings. They've gotten bolder,
대담해지고 있고
and,as the satellite corruption proves,more sophisticated.
위성에 침입한 걸로 보듯
더욱 세련되어졌지
If FARC takes the border area,
파크가 국경지역을
점거한다면
파나마를 직접 압박해서
they could drive into Panama itself
운하 지역을
공격할 수 있어
and conceivably overtake the Canal Zone.
This represents a very real danger to U.S. interests.
미국의 이익에 심각한 위험이
될 수 있다는 거야
NASA wants a discreet domestic inquest
나사에선 위성 관리
프로그램에 대해서
신중한 국내조사를
원하고 있어
into its satellite maintenance program.
If this can happen to one U.S. satellite,
it could happen to all of them.
하나의 미국 위성에
일어날 수 있는 일이면
모든 위성에
일어날 수 있으니까
Jai,I want you and Annie to work on the inquest team,
제이, 애니를 데리고
조사팀을 맡아
리바와 함께해
along with Reva.
Who's Reva?
리바가 누구죠?
Auggie's replacement.
No one can ever replace Auggie Anderson,
오기의 후임이에요
누구도 오기 앤더슨을
대신할 수 없어, 하지만...
but Reva Kline,everyone.
리바 클라인이야
모두들
Reva came from science and technology
과학기술부서에서 왔고
where she was the youngest lead project manager
역대 가장 젊은 나이로
프로젝트 수석 책임자를
역임했어
ever to hold that position. Let's make her feel at home.
다들 환영해주도록 해
Hi. It's good to be here.
안녕하세요
오게 돼서 기뻐요
영자막 elderman
www.addic7ed.com
-==팎읔襟있蹈==-
굶俚캥쏭묩欺構슥직，拮쐐痰黨庚둡촐
-==http://www.ragbear.com==-
줅소큽景묏 뒤랗센뒤5섞
Season 2 Episode 5
Around the Sun
-=팎읔襟俚캥莉=-
럇陋：
叫뚤：
珂쇌菉:kami
한글번역 에렝아이
디시인사이드 기미갤
발 페달이에요?
Is that your pedal foot?
Ha ha. Very funny.
아주 웃겼어요
Annie's a fast driver.
애니는 차를
빨리 몰거든
My sister wants us to do the Marine Corps Marathon.
언니가 해병대 마라톤에
나가자고 해서
Training started last night.
Is she married?
어젯밤부터
연습 시작했어요
결혼하신 분인가요?
Yeah.
네
What?
왜요?
Nothing.
아무것도 아니에요
그냥...
It's just that in 35% of failed marriages
실패한 결혼의
35%에서
the wife usually takes up a sport or a pastime
아내가 이혼의 징후로
스포츠와 취미에
as a precursor to divorce.
집중하는 모습을 보이죠
Although running is a really great way to work things out.
그래도 달리기가
좋은 해결책이긴 하죠
게다가 상담치료보다
저렴하잖아요?
Besides,it's cheaper than therapy,right?
Okay,so,Annie,you're going to use your Smithsonian NOC
to infiltrate NASA.
좋아요, 그럼 애니는
스미소니언 신분으로
나사에 잠입하세요
Great,I can use all that knowledge I got at Space Camp
when I was 12.
12살 때 우주 캠프에서 배운
지식을 활용할 수 있겠네요
당신이 우주광일 줄은
전혀 몰랐네요
I had no idea you were a space geek.
Get to know me.
나랑 더 친해져야겠네요
마지막 미개척지라고요
It's the final frontier.
Space,I mean. Not me.
우주 말이에요
나 말고요
Reva,what do you think of space exploration?
리바, 우주 탐험에 대해
어떻게 생각해?
비용을 생각하면
If you look at the numbers,
the NASA missions waste in inordinate amount of our nation's science budget.
나사의 활동은 국가 과학
예산에 지나친 낭비예요
Do you honestly think you can put a price
우주를 개척하는
용감한 탐험에
on bold explorations of new frontiers in space?
가격을 매길 수
있다고 생각해요?
I try to.
그러려고
하고 있어요
I have a spreadsheet here if you'd like to see it.
스프레드시트로 계산한 걸
보여드릴 수도 있어요
Okay,mission.
좋아요
임무를 보자면...
Annie,you'll head down to NASA headquarters on "E" street.
애니, E 거리에 있는
나사 본부로 가요
There's a Mars day reception in the lobby.
로비에서 화성의 날
행사가 열리는데
NASA employees and their families will be there.
나사 직원들과 가족들이
와 있을 거예요
You'll take the oral histories of four NASA staffers
위성 관리에 관여하는
직원들의 구술을 들으면 돼요
who contributed to the maintenance of the satellite.
And I'll take your video
저는 비디오를 통해
and use facial and body language micro-expression analysis
표정과 몸짓의
미세 표현을 분석해서
to hone in on potential suspects.
잠재적 용의자를
추려낼 거예요
그럼 제 인터뷰를 보면서
알아낸다는 거군요?
So you're gonna watch my interviews and look for tells,
like in poker?
포커처럼?
이건 카드 게임의
원초적인 직감이 아니에요
It's not a primitive gut instinct like in a card game.
It works.
- 효과가 있어요
- 애니...
Annie,you'll ask four general questions.
당신은 네 가지
일반적인 질문을 할 거예요
세 가지는 핵심 질문을 위한
사전 작업이죠
Three of which are lead-ups to the control trigger question.
한 가지 더요
And one more thing,budget cuts at NASA have been severe.
나사의 예산 삭감이
심각한 상태예요
그러니 실망하지 마요
그쪽의 의욕이...
So don't be disappointed if morale--
Isn't as high as yours.
당신처럼 충만하지
않더라도요
Okay.
이상이에요
You're still here with us regular folk.
여전히 우리처럼 평범한
사람과 어울리고 있군요
Bureaucracy never ceases to amaze me.
관료주의가 끊임없이
날 놀라게 해요
I had to fill out 12 forms
just to get this key card for the seventh floor,
서류를 12건이나
작성한 다음에야
7층으로 가는
키카드를 발급 받았어요
where I have to fill out more forms.
작성할 서류가
더 쌓여있는 곳이죠
나사에서 과학자와 비행사에
대한 조사를 의뢰했어요
NASA wants us to investigate scientists and astronauts.
Well,if NASA's requesting it,it's an internal audit,
나사가 의뢰했다면
내부 감사니까
so you're not breaching CIA charter. It still feels weird.
CIA 헌장
위배는 아니에요
그래도 이상한
기분이 들어요
Because it's Americans or because it's NASA?
미국인이라서요?
아니면 나사라서?
Both.
둘 다요
조안도 당신 기분을 알고
당신을 뽑은 걸 거예요
Joan knows how you feel.
That's probably why she picked you.
Why is that?
어째서요?
Because she knows you care enough to get this right.
당신이라면 이 일을
바로잡기 위해
충분히 주의를
기울일 테니까요
Now I don't know if you caught that,but I just hit seven.
눈치챘나
모르겠는데
방금 7층을 눌렀어요
정보위원회의 제 반대자들이
속도를 올리고 있습니다
My opponents on the intelligence committee are gaining momentum.
They're prepared to ask for an investigation
and hearings into Arthur as early as next week.
아서에 대한
조사와 청문회를
이르면 다음 주에
준비할 거예요
최소한 우리가
듣기론 그렇습니다
At least that's what we're hearing.
Maybe you know something else.
당신은 뭔가 더
알지도 모르겠군요
Chet?
체트?
Are you sure this is decaf?
이거 정말
디카페인 맞나요?
Positive.
물론입니다
Yeah. Don't worry about hearings.
네... 청문회는
걱정하지 마세요
Those clowns on the intelligence committee
정보위원회의 광대들은
자신들이 옳음을
증명해야 할 겁니다
have to justify their jobs.
You're in good hands with me.
제가 처리하죠
So listen,I have a tennis date in Hilton Head.
그게 말이죠
제가 힐튼 헤드에서
테니스 모임이 있어서요
We'll revisit when I get back.
제가 돌아오면
다시 논의하기로 하죠
I'm confused.
혼란스럽군
Are we rescheduling the meeting?
회의 시간을
변경한 거야?
아니면 방금이
회의였던 거야?
Or was that the meeting?
♬ All the Things We Do ♬
Jasmine Ash
어떻게 나사에서
일하게 되셨나요?
How did you come to work for NASA?
I was a double major
물리학과 항공 공학을
이중 전공했어요
in Physics and Aeronautical Engineering.
Not everyone can work on ozone mapping spectrometers.
누구나 오존 지도 분광계를
다룰 순 없죠
With a minor in Applied Mathematics.
부전공은
응용 수학이었죠
공군이었죠
"날아서 싸우고 이긴다"
Air Force. Fly,fight,win.
I had PhDs in Musical Theory and practical philosophy.
음악 이론과 실천 철학에
박사 학위가 있어요
I've always wanted to work for NASA
언제나 나사에서
일하고 싶었습니다
since I was a little boy.
꼬마 때부터요
현재 하고 계시는 일이
정확히 뭔가요?
What are you working on specifically right now?
T.O.M.S, 화산 배출물 조사
오존 지도 제작이요
T.O.M.S. volcanic emissions,ozone mapping.
I'm an astronaut.
전 우주 비행사입니다
I supervise a team of technicians
기술자들을
감독하는 일입니다
in the satellite maintenance office.
위성 관리국
기술자들이죠
We always have a contingency plan,
우린 언제나 긴급 사태에
대비하고 있고
and no program is green lit
발생가능한 모든 외적 영향에
해결책을 강구하기 전까진
until we know every solution to every possible externality.
어떠한 프로그램도
승인되지 않습니다
Where do you see yourself in five years?
Out of H.Q. in D.C.
5년 후엔 어디서
일하고 계실까요?
본부가 있는
워싱턴을 벗어나
and down to Canaveral where the action happens.
발사가 이뤄지는
커내버럴에서요
Space.
우주죠
Did I mention to you I was an astronaut?
제가 우주 비행사라고
얘기했던가요?
네
Can I--I'm sorry,can I go now?
저기, 죄송한데
그만 가도 될까요?
I'm a NASA guy,so I'll probably be working right here.
저는 나사맨이기 때문에
여기서 일하지
않을까 싶습니다
Tell her how close you came to serving
우주 탐사 대통령 특별위원회에
들어갈 뻔했던 이야기해요
on the Presidential Commission for Space Exploration.
That's not a plant. He's my son,Charlie.
심어둔 게 아닙니다
제 아들인 찰리입니다
My dad should be in the Smithsonian.
아빠는 스미소니언
박물관으로 가셔야 해요
Basically started working for NASA when he was ten.
열 살 때부터 나사에서
일하셨으니까요
I saw the Apollo 15 space launch at Cape Canaveral.
아폴로 15호 발사를
케이프 커내버럴에서 지켜봤죠
Really?
정말이요?
Yes,my folks drove down from Charlottesville in our Ford Country Squire station wagon.
네, 가족끼리 샬러츠빌부터
운전해갔죠
포드 컨트리 스퀘어
스테이션웨건으로요
What's your favorite mission,Charlie?
Pioneer Ten.
제일 좋아하는
탐사선이 뭐야, 찰리?
파이오니어 10호요
Back from the dead and 7 billion miles away.
죽음에서 돌아와
70억 마일을 여행했죠
And still going. See ya,Earth.
여전히 가고 있지
"또 봐요, 지구"
I'm with Carl Sagan on that.
전 칼 세이건 편이에요
We're just a pale-blue dot.
우린 창백한 푸른 점이죠
칼 세이건의 저서
Excuse me.
실례합니다
I oversee all multimedia projects at the Smithsonian,
저는 스미소니언의 멀티미디어
프로젝트 전부를 살펴보는데
and the first I've heard of this film is a phone call I got about 15 minutes ago.
이 영화에 대해선 15분 전
전화로 처음 들었어요
Who exactly signed off on your project?
정확히 누가 당신의
프로젝트를 승인했죠?
Dennis Stephens.
데니스 스티븐스요
I have no idea who that is.
누군지 전혀 모르겠군요
I'm calling--
The Board of Directors,he's on it.
- 전화해보죠
- 이사회예요?
그분도 이사예요
He's in charge of fundraising for the next two years,
앞으로 2년간
세계 유산 기금을 포함해
including the Heritage Fund.
모금 활동을
담당하게 되시죠
- You familiar with that? - Yes,I am.
- 모르시나요?
- 물론 알죠
Sorry to interrupt.
- 방해해서 죄송해요
- 아뇨, 괜찮아요
No,it's no problem.
죄송해요
The irony of a view you can't enjoy
is not lost on me.
자네가 경치를
즐기지 못한다고
달리 영향받진 않았네
I didn't want to give you a different office
just 'cause you can't appreciate blue skies.
푸른 하늘을
감상하지 못한다고
다른 사무실을
주고 싶진 않았어
By the way,we replicated your D.P.D. workstation to the inch.
그건 그렇고, 자네의 DPD
업무 환경을 정확히 재현했네
정확하진 않습니다
Not exactly.
You added state-of-the-art speakers
and some other goodies.
최첨단 스피커를
추가해주셨군요
다른 멋진
도구들도 있고요
Catered lunch at 1:00 p.m.
전용 식당은
오후 1시야
You're in the big leagues now.
자넨 이제 빅리그에
올라온 거야
Wow,you've really made this place your own.
어느새 자기 공간으로
만들었군요
순식간에요
And so quickly.
Annie,I had to sift through
a lot of your NASA interview footage.
애니, 당신의 인터뷰 영상을
샅샅히 조사해야 했어요
Next time try to put the control question
다음번엔 핵심 질문을
in the same place during each interview.
각 인터뷰마다 동일한
순서에 하도록 해요
You varied it once. Duly noted.
- 한번 순서를 바꿨더군요
- 잘 알겠습니다
In 84% of perjury cases,
위증 사건의 84%에서
the subjects display common physical behaviors,
대상자는 동일한
행동을 보여요
and in 70% of those cases,they actually try to hide themselves.
70%의 경우엔 자신을
가리려는 행동을 하죠
They put up a physical barrier like an arm.
팔 같은 걸로
물리적 장벽을 치는 거죠
What are you working on specifically right now?
현재 하고 계시는 일이
정확히 뭔가요?
I,um,I supervise a team of technicians
제 일은...
기술자들을
감독하는 일입니다
in the satellite maintenance office. That's it?
위성 관리국
기술자들이죠
- 이게 다예요?
- 이게 단서였죠
That's our start.
팔을 허리에
올린 게 신호죠
The arm across his waist is the tell,
so we dug deeper.
그래서 더 자세히
분석해봤죠
The tensile quality in his oculi and oris muscles
눈과 입 주변 근육의
긴장 정도가
is inconsistent during this answer.
이 대답을 하는 동안
자주 변해요
An involuntary sign of deceit.
무의식적인
기만의 표현이죠
Or he was just nervous.
He's got motive.
아니면 그냥
긴장한 거겠죠
동기가 있어요
NASA refused to fund his project on satellite refueling six months ago.
나사에선 6개월 전
위성 연료 재공급에 관한
그의 프로젝트에
지원을 거부했어요
His wife left him last year.
작년엔 아내가 떠났죠
And while he was initially admitted to NASA
게다가 처음에 우주 비행사
프로그램을 통해
through the astronaut program,he never got to go up in space.
나사에 들어왔지만
우주에 나가보지 못했죠
거기서 인터뷰한
모든 사람 중에
Of all the guys I interviewed there,
will was the only one cut from genuine NASA cloth.
윌만이 나사 본연에
충실한 사람이었어요
나사 공학자들의
봉급과 대우는 형편없어요
NASA engineers are poorly paid and underappreciated,
two qualities that fit the treasonous profile.
반역자의 프로파일에
부합하는 두 가지 특징이죠
We need to get him under surveillance.
감시를 붙여야겠어요
That's N.S.A. purview.
그건 NSA의 관할이잖아요
국가 안보국
We'll get Joan to liaise with Fort Meade.
조안에게 포트 미드의
협력을 얻어달라고 해야죠
No. No way. Absolutely not.
안 돼
절대로 안 돼
A wiretap means we're in bed with N.S.A.
도청장치는 NSA와
함께한다는 뜻이고
And they would control the legacy switch.
그쪽에서 레거시 스위치를
통제하려 할 거야
Sorry.
미안해
Uh,an R1 wire transmitter
R1 와이어 송신기는
레거시 스위치를
피해 갈 수 있어요
could get around the legacy switch.
Supersede the rule of law?
법망을 피해서 말이지?
Destroy our tenuous relationship with justice and the N.S.A.?
If you'll let me just finish--
정의와의 미약한 관계마저
끊자고? NSA와의 관계도?
마저 설명 드리면...
안 돼
No.
Reva,you're new,
리바, 너는 신입이지
내 부서에서 일이 어떻게
진행되는지 알려주지
so I'll let you in on the way things work in my division.
There is no socratic method here.
My decisions are final.
여기선 밀고 당기기
같은 거 없어
내 결정은
최종적인 거야
괜찮아요?
You okay?
Um,I'm fine. I just have allergies.
괜찮아요
알레르기가 있어서요
오늘 꽃가루 계측이
8.5예요
The pollen counts are at 8.5.
Just so you know,you're not the first person
Joan's bawled-out on their first day.
첫날부터 조안이 호통친 사람은
당신이 처음이 아니에요
Really? She's actually kind of cool.
그래요?
사실 조안은 제법...
쿨해요
Well,maybe not cool,but not so bad
쿨하진 않더라도
그렇게 나쁘진 않아요
once you figure her out.
언젠가 이해하게
될 거예요
In D.S.T. we didn't have to figure out people.
과학기술부에선 사람을
이해할 필요가 없었어요
We just generated files and charts and studies and--
파일이나 도표를 만들고
연구를 진행하면 됐죠
I transferred here to the D.P.D.
내가 DPD로 온 건
because I wanted more of a challenge.
더욱 어려운 도전을
원했기 때문이에요
And clearly I've gotten it.
확실히 더 어려운
도전이었네요
Around here,it's a bit more of a two-way street,
여기 일은 조금 더
양 방향이에요
human intelligence and hard facts.
인적 정보와
엄격한 사실들에 대해서요
Yeah.
알았어요
- 일방향 감시는 어때요?
- 집을 도청하자고요?
What about one-way surveillance? Bug their home?
Why not? We could do it ourselves.
왜요? 그건 단독으로
할 수 있어요
한쪽의 통화만
들을 수 있잖아요
We'd only hear one side of the phone call.
But we'd hear everything that was going on in their house.
그래도 집에서 일어나는
모든 일을 들을 수 있어요
We'd maintain jurisdiction over the investigation,
and we wouldn't have to interface with N.S.A.
조사의 관할권을
유지하면서
NSA와 접촉하지
않아도 돼요
That'll work.
될 거예요
How should we get inside their house?
어떻게 집안으로
들어갈 수 있을까요?
Create a diversion? Call in a bomb threat?
주의를 돌려서?
폭발물 신고를 해서?
그럼 FBI에 알려야 하는데
그런 건 바라지 않아
No,that's likely to tip off the FBI,and we don't want that.
How 'bout this?
이건 어때요?
What are you doing?
뭐하는 거예요?
Are you calling the target?
목표 대상에게
전화하는 거예요?
- 여보세요
- 안녕하세요, 윌이에요?
- Hello. - Hey,is this Will?
네, 누구시죠?
Yes. Who's this?
저는 스미소니언의
애니 워커예요
This is Annie Walker from the Smithsonian.
I filmed you for Mars day.
화성의 날 행사 때
촬영했었죠
If was wondering if I couldn't drop off a photo we have here
협조에 감사드리는 뜻으로
저희가 가진 사진을 한 장
증정해 드리고 싶어서요
as a small thank you for doing our piece.
- Today? - Yeah,today'd be great.
- 오늘이요?
- 네! 오늘 좋아요
I could even take you guys out for a bite.
제가 한 끼 대접해
드릴 수도 있어요
찰리와 옥상에서 바비큐를
할 계획이었는데요
Charlie and I were planning to grill on the rooftop.
Nothing special of course. You're welcome to come.
뭐 특별한 건 없지만
오시면 좋겠네요
Around 6:30 or 7:00? I love a good barbecue.
6시 반이나
7시 괜찮을까요?
저도 바비큐 좋아해요
I'll see you tonight.
저녁에 봬요
Annie,when you were up at NASA,
did anything seem out of the ordinary?
애니, 나사에 갔을 때
뭔가 특이한 일 없었나요?
Uh,P.R. rep asked me what I was doing,
홍보부 직원이
무슨 일이냐고
묻긴 했는데
처리했어요
but I handled it. You handled it?
처리했다고요?
Did it ever occur to you
어제 당신의 위장이
발각됐다는 생각은 안 들어요?
that you might have blown your cover yesterday?
I mean,what are the chances of them having a barbecue
당신이 초대한
바로 그날
바비큐를 계획할 확률이
얼마나 되겠어요?
the night you invite yourself over?
This is a trap.
이건 함정이에요
You get all that?
다 된 건가?
네
Yes.
And are we responding to a request
우리가 요청을
받았기 때문에
세 건의 아프가니스탄
작전을 공개하는 건가요?
to declassify these three Afghanistan missions?
이건 자발적인 거야
내 투명성 확보의 일환이지
This is voluntary.
It's part of my transparency push.
Some of our assets in Kashmir
have used their influence to open up the region.
카슈미르의
우리 정보원들이
영향력을 발휘해
지역을 개방하도록 했어
Yes,sir.
알겠습니다
And,Auggie,have some fun with this.
그리고 오기...
좀 즐기도록 하게
We built a school for girls.
우린 여자아이들을
위한 학교를 지었어
It's the feel-good hit of the summer.
이런 게 잘 통하는
한 방이지
Yes,sir.
알겠습니다
안녕하세요
들어오세요
Come on in.
Apollo 15. You remembered.
아폴로 15호군요
기억해주셨군요
I thought you'd appreciate it.
좋아하실 거
같았어요
Thank you.
고맙습니다
I swear,the sun was brighter back then.
사진보다
더 맑았던 거 같군요
I'm sure that's just 'cause Florida is closer to the equator.
플로리다가 적도에
더 가까워서 그럴 거예요
Charlie is upstairs lighting the coals.
찰리는 위층에서
불을 피우고 있어요
Can I get you something to drink?
마실 걸 가져다
드릴까요? 맥주?
- Beer? - Sure.
좋아요
It's clean.
세탁한 겁니다
It's just we're not big folders around here.
No judgment.
저희가 정리에
조금 게을러서요
신경 쓰지 마세요
올라갈까요?
Should we go upstairs?
I'm hungry too. Let's go.
저도 배가 고프네요
어서 가시죠
Remember,Annie,
you need to give Jai coverage in the apartment
기억해요, 애니
제이가 도청 장치를
설치할 시간을
from 7:00 to 7:15 for the surveillance installation.
7시부터 7시 15분까지
벌어줘야 해요
Don't come down from the roof until 7:15.
7시 15분까지 옥상에서
내려오면 안 돼요
First star of the night,dad. Antares beat Scorpio.
오늘 밤 첫 번째
별이에요, 아빠
안타레스가 전갈자리보다
먼저네요
Oh,there's Bo?tes.
아! 저기
목동자리예요
- I can just see Spica. - Where?
- 스피카도 보이네
- 어디요?
It's nice you guys take the time to come and do this once in a while.
여러분 멋지네요
이렇게 가끔 함께
시간을 보내시는군요
Not just once in a while.
가끔이 아닙니다
I come home from work to look at the stars with Charlie
저는 매일 밤 퇴근하고
찰리와 별을 관찰한답니다
every night no matter what.
무슨 일이 있어도요
Let's eat.
드시죠
Delphinus was the first constellation I ever learned.
돌고래자리가 제가
처음 배운 별자리예요
My dad taught me.
아버지가 알려주셨죠
I got chicken pox the first day before third grade.
3학년이 되기 하루 전에
수두에 걸렸는데
He carried me out into the backyard,
절 뒷마당으로
데리고 나가셔서
pointed straight up,and told me the story of Delphinus.
돌고래자리를
가리키시면서
얽힌 이야기를
해주셨어요
So every autumn when you look at the small cluster of Delphinus,
그럼 매년 가을 돌고래자리
성단을 볼 때면
you must think of him. Yeah,I do.
아버님 생각을
하겠군요
맞아요
Charlie,set up the telescope.
찰리? 망원경을
준비해라
Come on.
오세요
Are,uh,you married or anything?
혹시...
결혼하셨거나
그런 가요?
Uh,not that I know of.
내가 아는 한
그렇지 않은데
You should hang out with my dad.
He's really cool.
우리 아빠와
만나보세요
정말 멋진 분이에요
I mean,he can be kind of a dork sometimes,
때때로 바보 같은
구석도 있지만
but he built this telescope.
이 망원경도
만드셨어요
It is impressive.
그 점은 인상 깊네
I know our apartment looks really depressing,
우리 집이 정말
우중충해 보이는 건 알지만
but it's just 'cause my dad never asks for a raise.
아빠가 월급 인상 같은 걸
요구한 적이 없어서 그래요
He doesn't believe in asking for anything.
He's really proud about that.
뭐라도 요구하질
않는 분이죠
그 점을 자랑스러워 하세요
- What about you? - Nah,not so much.
- 너는 어떤데?
- 별로 아빠 같진 않아요
I've got my eye on a really sweet Vespa.
요즘 눈독 들이고 있는
스쿠터가 있어요
Wow,the weatherman's finally right.
기상청이 맞을 때도 있네요
Storm's on its way.
폭풍우가 오는군요
Better get downstairs.
아래층으로
내려가야겠어요
실은 저는 아직
좀 배고프네요
Actually,I'm still hungry.
Could I have one more bratwurst?
소시지 하나만
더 먹을 수 있을까요?
Yeah,I got you loud and clear.
그래, 아주 잘 들려
Walking through right now talking out loud like a crazy person.
집안을 돌아다니면서
미친 사람처럼 떠들고 있어
제대로 들려?
You got that?
FADING OUT.
빠져나와요
Okay,I'm gonna set one more. It's all we've got time for.
알았어, 하나 더 설치할게
그럴 시간밖에 안 돼
FIVE MINUTES.
5분
정말 맛있어요
This was really good. You can take that downstairs.
들고 내려가셔도 돼요
빗속에서 드실 필요 없어요
You don't have to eat it out in the rain.
Just made it.
간신히 맞춰 내려왔네요
Oh,uh,I left my sweater upstairs.
스웨터를 위에
두고 왔어요
You guys head on down. I'll get it.
먼저 내려가세요
제가 가져올게요
Thanks,Charlie.
고맙다, 찰리
Feel great.
기분이 괜찮아
Had a light supper.
식사도 가볍게 했고
Went to bed early. I slept like a rock.
일찍 잠자리에 들어서
곤히 잤어
Yeah,I ate too much and went to bed late.
난 과식한데다
늦게 잤지만
But thanks.
고마워
Hey,can I ask you something? Sure.
- 하나 물어봐도 돼?
- 그럼
Is everything okay with you and Michael?
형부랑 별일 없는 거야?
I know he's been traveling a lot.
It's fine.
출장이 너무 잦잖아
괜찮아
I mean,it's weird. It's hard to explain.
좀 이상해
설명하기 힘들어
Try me.
I mean,it's nothing earth-shattering.
해봐
그러니까 놀랄 일
없다는 거야, 그냥...
- It's just... - Danielle,what is it?
언니, 왜 그래?
I don't miss him much.
별로 그립지가 않아
At all.
전혀
- Danielle,I'm so-- - No,it's fine.
- 언니, 정말...
- 아니야! 괜찮아
That's what's so crazy. I'm fine.
쓸데없는 소릴 했다
난 괜찮아
What happened?
무슨 일이야?
I don't know.
나도 모르겠어
Do you think it's possible to...
넌 그런 일이
가능할 거 같니?
slowly fall out of love with someone?
누군가에 대한 사랑이
천천히 식어가는 거?
어떻게 생각해?
얘?
Any thoughts? Hello?
Let's keep running and talking.
뛰면서 얘기하자
So I don't know whether I should talk to Michael.
마이클에게 얘기해야
하는 건지 잘 모르겠어
Annie.
애니?
Hey,slow down! I just wanna finish. You wanna win!
천천히 가
난 그만 하고 싶은데
뭘 그렇게 달려
Sorry.
미안해
Danielle,I wanna talk about this,
언니, 얘기하고
싶긴 한데
but I realized I just dropped my phone back there.
뛰다가 전화기를
떨어뜨린 것 같아
The museum's gonna kill me.
It has everyone's home number on it.
박물관에서
가만 안 있을 거야
모든 사람들
집 전화번호가 있거든
- Well,I'll help you. - No,uh,don't.
내가 도와줄게
아니야, 됐어
Go home.
Please.
집에 가
응?
The girls have to get ready for school.
애들 학교 보낼
준비해야 하잖아
- Well,I'll call-- - No,you can't.
- 전화 하면...
- 그렇겐 안 돼
'Cause you don't have your phone,and I dropped mine.
전화기 안 들고 왔잖아
난 떨어뜨렸고
I'll be careful. I promise.
조심할게
약속해
Okay.
그래
- Hey,Annie. - I was surveilled this morning.
- 네, 애니
- 아침에 미행이 붙었어요
I need you to get in touch with Rock Creek Park police
록크리크 공원 경찰에
연락해서
공원 도로에서 있었던
연쇄 충돌 사고에
and see if anyone I.D.'d
a female involved in a parkway pileup.
연관된 여성을 알아본 사람이
있었는지 확인해줘요
Blue top with a long braid.
Okay,will do.
파란 상의에
길게 땋은 머리예요
알았어요
그러죠
As for you,protocol directive 2408.
당신은 명령 규정
2408번을 따라요
Got it. I'll watch my tail.
알았어요
미행 주의하죠
No. That means you shouldn't come in today.
아뇨, 그건 오늘 오면
안 된다는 거예요
Not gonna happen.
그런 일은
없을 거예요
I'm in sticker shock.
충격적인 비용이네
It's not even itemized.
심지어 항목도
나눠져있지 않아
Neither are our bills to Congress.
의회에 들어간
우리 비용도 마찬가지지
He knew we had nowhere else to turn,
우리가 달리
기댈 곳도 없고
배부른 변호사가
필요하다는 것도 알면서
he knew we needed a fat cat attorney,
and he got us to dip into our retirement funds
for a tennis vacation in Hilton Head?
우리 은퇴 자금으로
힐튼 헤드에서 테니스를 쳐?
Yeah,don't personalize it.
개인적으로
받아들이지 마
I was wrong...
내가 틀렸어
to insist that we hire him.
체트를 고용하자고
우기는 게 아니었어
So what should we do?
이제 어떻게
해야 하지?
I need you to be every bit as gallant
나는 당신이...
내가 아는 당신만큼
용감해졌으면 좋겠어
as I know you can be. This doesn't sound good.
별로 좋은 소리가
아닌 거 같은데
I need you to pay him,
체트에게 비용을 지불하고
and then I need you to fire him.
그런 다음 체트를
해고했으면 좋겠어
Please.
그렇게 해줘
- 오늘...
- 미행 없었어요
- I thought you-- - I wasn't tailed.
How can you be sure?
I took three buses,two Metro lines,
어떻게 확신해요?
버스를 세 번
지하철은 두 번 갈아 탔고
기관 버스가 정문 앞에
내려줬어요
and the Agency jitney dropped me off at the front door.
All in all,
제 주차공간을 생각하면
대중교통이 오히려 낫네요
I'd say public transportation's a better deal than my parking spot.
Your boy Will has an active nightlife.
윌의 밤생활이
화려하더군요
공원에서 날 미행한 여자예요
윌과 함께 있었어요?
That was the woman who tailed me in the park.
She was with Will?
어젯밤이에요
당신이 떠난 직후죠
Last night,almost immediately after you left.
Then will came back home and we got this.
윌은 집으로 돌아와
이런 통화를 했죠
I have another drop. Same time and place.
넘겨줄 게 또 있습니다
시간과 장소는 동일합니다
Will's our guy.
윌이 범인이었군요
Auggie.
오기
This press release about our missions,the school,
이 발표 내용은
우리 작전, 학교...
my efforts to open up the Agency... Yes,sir.
기관의 개방을 위한
나의 노력에 관한 거군
그렇죠
It reads like Crime and Punishment,
except with no information in it.
아무런 정보가
없다는 점만 빼면
죄와 벌을 읽는
기분이야
You're maddeningly obtuse.
자네 정말 둔감하군
If we're gonna depress the hell out of everyone,
사람들을
우울하게 할 거라면
let's not bother voluntarily declassifying anything.
굳이 자발적으로
정보를 공개할 필요 없어
I mean,Auggie...
내 말은, 오기...
We built a girls' school. A girls' school.
우린 여자 학교를
지었단 말이야
여자 학교를
그 내용은
추가했습니다만
And I included that. Along with vague,conditional information
표현은 모호하고
학교 자체의 목적은
about the purpose of the school itself.
가정적으로 드러나 있어
감질나게 하는 단계는
건너뛰도록 내가 도와주지
Let me save you some cat-and-mouse.
Girls will show up.
여자아이들이
나타날 거야
They will learn. Lives will improve.
학교를 다니게 되고
삶은 나아질 테지
It's straightforward.
간단한 거야
Now,I underestimated how difficult a transition
자네 같이 훌륭한
비밀 요원은
보직 변경이 어렵다는 점을
내가 과소평가했군
it would be for a good covert operative like yourself,
especially one with such talent on the battlefield.
특히나 전장에서 대단한
재능을 보였던 사람을 말이야
It's not difficult,sir.
어렵지 않습니다
I'm asking you to run against every instinct to maintain secrecy.
비밀을 유지하고자 하는
모든 본능을 거스르란 거야
I learned those skills. I can unlearn them.
저는 그런
기술들을 배웠죠
잊을 수 있습니다
Well,unlearn them quick.
The press conference is tomorrow.
그럼 빨리 잊게
기자 회견은 내일이야
Annie Walker and icy-hot menthol.
애니 워커와
파스 향이군요
Marathon training is no picnic.
마라톤 훈련이
만만치 않아서요
Hey,these new digs are incredible.
새 사무실은
정말 끝내주네요
이 방만 따로
온도조절도 되죠
Yeah,I've got my own thermostat.
And free lunch.
All I ever wanted was a job with free food.
공짜 점심도요
늘 공짜 점심 있는
직업을 꿈꿨었는데
하지만 내 일에 대해
이야기하려고 온 건 아니죠?
But you're not here to talk about my job,are you?
The D.P.D. has their NASA traitor dead to rights--
나사의 반역자에 대한
확실한 증거를 포착했어요
phone calls,surveillance photos--
전화 통화도 있고
감시 사진도 있는데
but something about it does not line up.
Talk to Reva.
- 뭔가 맞지 않아요
- 리바에게 말해요
I vetted her with Joan. She's good.
조안과 함께 심사했어요
뛰어난 요원이에요
- She's not you. - Annie.
- 당신이 아니잖아요
- 애니
I'd love to help you,but I can't.
돕고 싶지만
그럴 수 없어요
What do you mean you can't? You always know what to do.
그럴 수 없다뇨? 당신은
뭘 해야 할지 늘 알잖아요
I just bombed out on my first assignment for Arthur,
방금 아서를 위한
첫 번째 임무를 망쳤고
and I've gotta turn it around by the end of the day.
그걸 오늘까지
되돌려놔야 해요
You were the first friend I ever made at this Agency...
당신은 내가 기관에서
처음으로 사귄 친구였죠
And no one I have met here
당신보다 인상 깊었던 사람은
아무도 만나보지 못했어요
has impressed me more since.
You're gonna do great at this job.
당신은 잘 해낼 거예요
방금 한 이야기를
확실히 하고 싶군요
I wanna make it clear we're just talking.
You're free to go at any time.
언제든 가셔도 좋습니다
In the way I'm free to not take the field sobriety test?
음주 측정을 안 받아도
되는 것처럼요?
Meaning what?
무슨 뜻이죠?
Meaning that,by not talking,
말을 하지 않으면
유죄로 추정되느냐는
뜻입니다
it's a presumption of guilt.
We can talk about talking,
말을 할 것인지에 대해
말할 수도 있고
or we can talk.
그냥 말을 할 수도 있겠죠
Or we can sit and not talk.
이대로 말을
안 할 수도 있고요
I didn't know who they were at first.
처음엔 그들이
누군지 몰랐어요
- You know who they are now? - Colombian rebels.
- 지금은 알아요?
- 콜롬비아 반군이죠
I'm going to advise you to get an attorney...
변호사를 구하란
충고를 드리고 싶네요
Because we're gonna have to
hand our investigation over to the Feds.
우리는 우리 수사를 FBI에
넘겨야 하거든요
I'll tell you everything. I'm tired of lying.
전부 말씀드리죠
더는 거짓말하기 지쳤습니다
How did the Colombians make you?
어떻게 콜롬비아에서
당신을 움직였죠?
I don't understand.
How did they turn you?
무슨 말씀이죠?
어떻게 당신을
포섭했나요?
How did they convince you to spy for them?
어떻게 스파이 활동을
설득했나요?
I was at a science fair of Charlie's.
찰리의 과학 경시대회에
갔었습니다
He was a finalist in the national competition.
찰리가 전국 대회
결선에 올랐었죠
그 여자는 아주 매력적인
미국인이었습니다
She was a very attractive American woman
who said she was from the private sector.
민간 부문에
종사한다고 했죠
회사에서 제 작업에 관해
들었다고 했어요
She said her company had heard of my work
and that no price was too high
to woo me away from NASA.
절 나사에서 빼오기 위해
얼마든지 지불하겠다고 했죠
She works for FARC.
I know that now.
파크의 요원이군요
지금은 알고 있습니다
I knew that her company was coming at me
그 여자의 회사에서
절 유혹하려는 의도로
with a strategy of seduction,but I--
접근한 걸
알고 있었습니다만
I just didn't care.
After a couple of rough years
저는 상관하지 않았습니다
사적으로나 공적으로
힘든 몇 년을 보낸 뒤라
both personally and professionally,
she was a tonic.
그 여자가 활력소가 됐죠
Then what happened?
그리곤 무슨 일이 있었죠?
Then I met her again...
다시 만났죠
This time at the planetarium.
그때는 천문관에서
만났습니다
She asked me for a manual
메뉴얼에 관해
물어보더군요
that I'd written on,uh,satellite maintenance.
제가 작성한 위성 관리에
관한 메뉴얼이었죠
Which they could reverse engineer.
그쪽에서 위성을
역설계할 수 있었겠군요
So after you gave her the manual,
is that when she revealed who she worked for?
당신이 메뉴얼을
넘겨준 다음에
자신의 소속을 밝혔나요?
By that time,they had their hooks in me.
그때는 이미
빠져나올 수가 없었어요
They blackmailed me for more information
about the satellite.
위성에 관한 더 많은 정보를
넘기라고 절 협박했죠
I was-- I was trapped. You weren't trapped.
전 덫에 걸렸던 겁니다
당신은 덫에
걸린 게 아니었어요
You could have come to us
after handing over that first manual,
처음 메뉴얼을
넘겨준 다음에
우리를 찾아올 수도
있었지만
but you chose not to.
당신은 그러지
않는 걸 택했죠
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다
이야기하고 싶어?
You wanna talk about it?
There's nothing really to say.
별로 이야기할 거 없는데
Maybe it's just a temporary lull
그냥 일시적인
권태일 수도 있어
or a passing funk.
아니면 스쳐가는
불안함일 수도 있고
Michael's a good father.
형부는 좋은 아버지잖아
You always see the best in everyone.
넌 늘 사람들
장점을 보지
- Maybe I'm naive. - No.
순진해서 그런 건지도
아니야
I just need to take a beat and refocus.
난 그냥 한 박자 쉬고
다시 집중하면 돼
Why don't you go for a romantic night out?
형부랑 데이트
나가보는 건 어때요?
I'll watch the girls this weekend.
내가 주말 동안
애들 봐줄게
I could do that.
그래도 되겠다
윌의 재정 상태를
살펴보고 있는데
I'm just into Will's finances.
He listed NASA as a beneficiary of part of his 401k.
연금 일부의 상속인을
나사로 지정해뒀어요
So?
그래서요?
So this is not a guy
who hates his institution.
자기 소속 기관을 증오하는
사람이 아니란 거죠
Annie,you helped the D.P.D. nail NASA's mole,okay?
애니, 당신은 DPD를 도와
나사의 스파이를 잡았어요
이제 FBI의 손에 넘어갔으니
그만 넘어가는 게 어때요?
It's in the Feds' hands now. Can we move on?
Uh,normally this is the time where my former tech op
보통은 이럴 때
내 전임 기술요원이
would encourage me,support my gut instinct,
날 격려해줬는데요
내 직감을 지지해주고
내 조사를 도와줬죠
and assist in my research.
Have you heard of the hummingbird project?
벌새 프로젝트라고
들어봤어요?
Was that the one two years ago
2년 전 과학기술부에서
만들던 감시 기계 아닌가요?
where D.S.T. was making surveillance birds?
네, 야외에서의 대화를
감시할 수 있는
Yes,remote-controlled hummingbirds
that could monitor outdoor conversations.
원격조종 벌새였죠
I was behind that.
내가 참여했어요
And even after it failed a very critical test run
전파 방해 때문에
아주 중요한 시험 비행에
실패했지만
due to interference,
I kept pushing it. I couldn't let it go.
난 계속 밀어붙였죠
그냥 버릴 수 없었어요
Well,it sounds like a cool idea.
Well,it was.
괜찮은 생각처럼
들리는데요
그랬죠
Until we took it out to Camp Peary
for a second test run.
캠프 피어리에서 두 번째
시험 비행을 하기 전까지는요
There was one thing we didn't count on,was the weather.
우리가 한 가지
간과한 게 날씨였죠
I mean,when the wind blew,we couldn't control the damn things.
바람이 불면
통제할 수 없었어요
My blind faith in that project
그 프로젝트에 대한
내 눈먼 믿음이
set me back two years at the Agency.
날 기관에서
2년 뒤쳐지게 했어요
So...take some advice from me
그러니까
내 충고를 받아들여서
and get out of your own way.
당신만의 생각에서
벗어나도록 해요
We're done with the NASA operation.
나사 작전은
종료됐어요
Move on,okay?
넘어가요
알았죠?
You know what I get from that story?
내가 그 이야기에서
뭘 배웠는지 알아요?
You were fired up about something.
당신도 뭔가에 열정을
불태웠었다는 거예요
Auggie,you are the Ernest Hemingway of good news.
오기, 자넨 좋은 소식의
어네스트 헤밍웨이야
Turns out I was right. You're a natural at this.
결국 내가 옳았군
자넨 타고났어
You're a quick study.
자넨 빨리 배우고
You're gonna help move the Agency into a new era.
기관을 새 시대로
이끄는데 도움이 될 거야
Reporters are like tigers in captivity--
if you wanna clean the cage,
기자들이란 사육하는
호랑이와도 같지
우리를 청소하고 싶다면
you gotta distract 'em with a piece of meat.
고기 조각으로
주의를 돌려야 해
Many good operatives have come in from the cold.
많은 좋은 요원들이
신분을 드러내곤 했다네
Yes,sir.
알겠습니다
There is a life,
이런 인생도 있는 거야
a fulfilling life,for an overt officer,Auggie.
공개된 임원으로도
성취감 있는 인생을 살 수 있어
Come on,Auggie. It's time.
가자고, 오기
때가 왔어
Micro-expressions don't lie,right?
미세 표현은
거짓말을 하지 않죠?
Well,I don't like to use absolutes,but yes,
절대적이라고 하고 싶진
않지만, 맞아요
statistically,micro-expressions
are excellent baselines of truthfulness.
통계적으로 진실을 가려내는데
훌륭한 기준선이 되죠
팔이나 커피잔으로
물리적 장벽을 치는 건
And putting up a physical barrier,
like your arm or a coffee cup,
means a lie,right?
거짓말이란 뜻이죠?
- Right. - Okay.
- 맞아요
- 좋아요
How did they turn you?
어떻게 당신을
포섭했나요?
어떻게 스파이 활동을
설득했나요?
How did they convince you to spy for them?
I was at a science fair for Charlie.
찰리의 과학 경시대회에
갔었습니다
He was a,uh,
찰리가 전국 대회
결선에 올랐었죠
a finalist in the national competition.
Wait a second.
잠시만요
That's his tell.
이게 단서예요
Right?
You're right. He's lying.
맞죠?
맞아요
거짓말이에요
Exactly.
바로 그거예요
How could he be lying both times?
어떻게 양쪽 다
거짓일 수 있죠?
Somehow I knew that a beautiful filmmaker
왠지 당신 같이
아름다운 영화제작자가
who loves space was too good to be true.
우주까지 좋아한다는 건
비현실적이라 생각했어요
What happened to the aspiring astronaut?
야심 넘치던 우주 비행사는
어떻게 된 건가요?
Annie,
애니...
in the scope of things,I didn't ruin the world.
멀리 내다보자면
난 세상을 망친 게 아니에요
Life--or the expansion of the galaxy,for that matter--
인생은... 우주로 따지면
은하의 확장 같은 건
continues to go on for billions of years,
내가 있건 없건
수십억 년 동안 계속될 겁니다
with or without me.
We're just a pale-blue dot.
우린 그저 창백한
파란 점이죠
Charlie quoted Carl Sagan when he was talking about pioneer 10.
찰리가 파이오니어 10호
이야기를 하면서
칼 세이건의
그 말을 인용했었죠
It wasn't you they made at the science fair.
과학 경시대회에서 파크가
접근한 건 당신이 아니라
It was Charlie...
찰리였군요
Wasn't it?
그렇죠?
He was only a boy.
찰리는 아이일 뿐이었어요
A very smart 16-year-old boy.
아주 영리한
열여섯 짜리 아이였죠
And then she came along.
그 여자가 찰리에게
접근했어요
자신만의 야망이
있는 아이를
That's all it took to snag a kid
with his own ambitions,
포섭하기 위해선
그걸로 충분했죠
who also wanted his old man to be a hero again.
찰리는 자기 아버지가
다시 영웅이 되길 원했고요
어떻게 찰리가
정보를 취득했죠?
How'd he get the information?
At first it was just my resume.
처음엔
내 이력서에서였죠
Then it was a paper I wrote.
그다음엔 내가 작성한
서류에서였고요
He thought he was giving my work
찰리는 내 작업을 민간 기업에
넘기는 걸로 생각했어요
to someone in the private sector.
They told him that,just by doing that,
그들은 찰리에게
그것만으로
he had violated the State Secrets Act,
이미 국가비밀법을
위반했다고 말하면서
and they just kept asking for more.
계속 정보를 넘길 것을
요구했죠
When did they have you?
As soon as Charlie told me.
당신에겐 언제 접근했죠?
찰리가 내게
말하자마자요
I took over the relationship.
내가 그 관계를
물려받고
I gave them the information about the satellites,and...
위성에 관한 정보를
넘겨줬어요
I didn't know what else to do.
달리 할 수 있는 일을
몰랐어요
What did Charlie think was happening?
찰리는 어떻게 된 거라
생각했나요?
He thought I'd fixed it all.
찰리는 내가 일을
바로 잡았다고 생각했어요
He thought things were back to normal.
모든 게 정상으로
돌아갔다고 생각했죠
It's been hard since his mother left.
그 애 엄마가
떠난 뒤론 힘들었어요
But it wasn't over,was it? No.
하지만 끝난 게 아니었죠?
맞아요
Why the phone call?
전화는 뭐였어요?
When I walked you out of the building
바비큐파티를 마치고
당신을 배웅했을 때
after the barbecue...
I saw they left me a signal.
난 그들이 남긴
신호를 봤어요
There was a bike
자전거가 있었죠
locked up to the bus stop.
정류장에 매어져
있는 자전거는
That meant they wanted me to meet them immediately.
날 즉시 만나고 싶다는
신호였어요
What did they say at the meeting?
만나서
어떤 말을 들었죠?
Oh,they thought you might be on to me.
당신이 나에 관해
알고 있을지 모른다고요
When you walked in the building,they said someone followed you in
당신이 건물로 들어설 때
누군가 따라왔다고 하더군요
and climbed out the fire escape just when we came down from the rooftop.
우리가 옥상에서 내려올 때
비상계단으로 빠져나갔다고요
They assumed that you'd bugged my place.
집에 도청장치를
설치했을 거라 생각하더군요
Then why would you go home and make an incriminating phone call?
그럼 왜 집으로 가서
죄가 있는 것처럼
전화 통화를 한 거죠?
Wait...you were trying to get caught?
잠깐만요
잡히려고 그런 거예요?
That was just a message I left on my own voicemail.
그건 내 보이스메일에
남기는 메시지였어요
Once you were out to us,
FARC's pipeline to NASA's information
일단 당신이
우리에게 드러나면
파크가 나사의 정보를
얻을 통로는 닫히겠죠
would be shut down.
And Charlie would be useless to them.
찰리는 그들에게
소용없을 테고요
Well,what was your contingency plan?
그럼 당신의
대비책은 뭐였어요?
All of this.
이 모든 거죠!
This wasn't a space mission.
이건 우주 비행 임무 같은 게
아니었어요
I had to protect my son,
no matter what the cost.
난 어떤 대가를 치르든
아들을 보호해야 했어요
DPD 기술과
Reva.
리바?
Annie Walker. I remember you.
애니 워커
당신이 기억나네요
Auggie.
I'm back.
오기?
돌아왔어요
Because you missed me so much?
내가 너무 그리워서요?
Ah,you're good,
but you're not that good.
당신도 좋지만
그 정도까진 아니에요
I wasn't ready to blow my cover.
내 위장신분을 드러낼
준비가 안 됐었어요
Besides,you are clearly helpless without me.
게다가 나 없인 당신은
속수무책인 게 분명하니까요
Completely and utterly helpless.
전적으로, 완전히
속수무책이죠
Are you read in? Yeah. It's not over,Annie.
- 사안은 들었어요?
- 네, 아직 끝나지 않았어요
- Why? - Charlie made a call.
- 왜요?
- 찰리가 전화를 걸었어요
He offered to give up everything about his dad's research
윌을 놓아준다면
위성 랑데부 능력에 관한
on satellite rendezvous capacities if they'll let will go.
윌의 모든 자료를
넘기겠다고 했어요
He thinks will is being held by FARC?
윌을 억류하고 있는 게
파크라고 생각하는 거예요?
You gotta get to him before they do.
파크보다 먼저
찰리를 확보해야 해요
Charlie,listen to me.
찰리
내 말 잘 들어
Your dad's safe. We wanna help you.
아빠는 안전해
널 돕고 싶어
He told us about FARC. I'm here to protect you.
파크에 대해서 얘기 들었어
널 보호하러 온 거야
88개의 별자리가
88 constellations
move across the sky each year.
매년 하늘을
가로지릅니다
Cast your eyes upward toward the Northern Hemisphere,
눈을 들어 위를 보세요
북반구를 향해서요
어서!
and we will explore just one part
우리가 탐험하게 되는 건
of the celestial field that has mesmerized...
인간이 수천 년 동안 발견한
황홀한 천체의
일부분일 뿐입니다
Charlie,get the gun!
찰리!
총을 집어!
It's over. It's gonna be okay.
이제 끝났어
이제 괜찮아질 거야
다른 친척은 없니?
Do you have other relatives here?
I mean,who will you stay with?
누구와 지낼 거야?
My grandma for now.
일단은 할머니랑요
Downside,lots of chores. Upside,folded laundry.
단점은 심부름이고
장점은 정리된 세탁물이죠
When can I see my dad? I don't know yet.
언제 아빠와
만날 수 있을까요?
아직 모르겠어
하지만 내가 아는 건
What I do know is I've never seen two people
너와 네 아빠는 서로에게
정말 충실하다는 거야
so loyal to each other.
That will count for something,Charlie.
그리고 그건
아주 중요한 거야, 찰리
Come on. Let's call your grandmother.
가자, 할머니께
연락해야지
Chet,we wanted to talk to you.
Look,there's no reason to thank me.
체트, 얘기 좀 하고 싶군요
잠깐만요, 감사하실
필요 없습니다
This is what I do.
이게 제 일이니까요
That's what we wanted to talk about.
저희가 말하고
싶은 것도 그겁니다
I got him in the third set.
3세트 만에
제가 이겼죠
거짓말은 하지
않겠습니다
I'm not gonna lie to you.
We could be having a very different conversation
제 팔꿈치
부상이 도졌다면
지금과는 아주 다른
대화를 하고 있을 겁니다
if my tennis elbow had flared up.
We're talking about why we hired you.
왜 당신을 고용했는지
이야기하고 있었어요
Yeah,I know,Joanie. No hearings.
네, 알아요
조니
무슨 말인지 알았어요
Who do you think I was playing tennis with?
I have no idea.
누구와 테니스를 쳤다고
생각하십니까?
전혀 모르겠군요
The esteemed Senator from Kentucky.
켄터키 주의 존경받는
상원의원이죠
Jensen?
He told his committee this morning
젠슨?
오늘 아침에 위원회에서
there's no reason to pursue an investigation.
조사를 추진할 이유가 없다는
발언을 했답니다
Get some sleep,chief.
잠 좀 주무세요
국장님
♬ Wrong Miracle ♬
Ximena Sarinana
To everything in its place.
Hear,hear.
여기 모든 것을 위하여!
위하여!
What happens to you now,Reva?
Um,back to D.S.T.
당신은 어떻게
되는 거예요, 리바?
과학기술부로
돌아가요
but with a bump in pay grade.
하지만 봉급은
크게 올랐죠
거기 사람들은 우리만큼
재밌지 않을 거야
Hmm. They're nowhere near as much fun as we are.
But they're more predictable.
하지만 보다
예측가능한 사람들이죠
Oh,you say that like it's a compliment.
칭찬의 의미로
하는 말 같은데
Time for more drinks.
한 잔씩 더 해야겠군요
I gotta go. I have a date.
가야겠어요
데이트가 있어서요
- Well,well. - Ooh!
Here it is.
이거야
It's old. Did you find it?
오래 됐네요
이모가 찾은 거예요?
할아버지가
이모 생일선물로 준 거야
My dad gave it to me for my birthday
when I was just a little older than you.
이모가 너보다
조금 더 어렸을 때였어
You guys are really lucky,
너흰 정말 행운이야
오늘밤 이모가 돌봐줘서
그런 것만은 아니야
and not just because I'm babysitting tonight.
There's a really bright star I'm gonna show you.
진짜 밝게 빛나는
별을 보러가자
Plus there's a story to go with it.
거기에 얽힌
이야기도 해줄게
* the wrong miracle,'cause all I wanted was you *
* the wrong miracle,but I guess it will do *
피드백
whemie@gmail.com
팎읔襟俚캥莉
-==http://www.ragbear.com==-
뻑短속흙